

Andrejus Miasnikovas Senior Java Developer

Professional Profile

Senior software developer with seven years of Java/J2EE development experience. Self-motivated, strong sense of responsibility. Very passionate about technology, always trying out new tools, frameworks, languages. After work I like coming up with my own ideas of software that I myself would like to use. Then I choose something and try to implement it. Whenever there's any time left trying to write about some of the stuff in my blog. I believe that at work it's important to be surrounded by competent people and have good and honest communication within the team. Even though it sounds like a given but it's only when these things are missing that you come to realize how important these things are.

Education

Sep 2005 - Jul 2007 Vilnius University

Field: IT and Telecommunications

Degree: Master's Degree Specialty: Informatics

Sep 2001 - Jul 2005 Vilnius University

Field: IT and Telecommunications

Degree: Bachelor's Degree Specialty: Informatics

Work Experience

Apr 2011 - Present Pixelmator Team

Software Developer

Working on image editing software that runs exclusively on Mac OS and is written in Objective-C. Tasks include modifying the UI look and feel, creating image processing filters that run on the GPU, improving the reading/writing compatibility of other image file formats.

Senior Java Developer

Worked on agile projects using the Scrum methodology with technologies like Liferay, JSF, Hibernate, Spring Framework, jBPM, ActiveMQ, CUPS, Maven2 and Selenium. Because we were able to use any IDE we wanted I chose IntelliJ IDEA and converted most of the team members to use it too. Main responsibilities included use-case design, implementation and documentation, unit and integration tests, continuos integration management. I was also responsible for assuring high availability of the application and making sure it scales well on several Linux nodes. I maintained the production environment by managing MySQL DB, took care of application deployment and installation, wrote scripts to automate common tasks on the servers. Was taken on-board of an event-based project with a very tight schedule which ran the risk of not delivering on time. Was responsible for fixing critical bugs and helping finish the implementation. The application was delivered on time and executed successfully.

Senior Java Developer

Main responsibilities included writing new and managing existing web applications, creating middleware solutions to allow internal systems communicate with each other, finding ways to automate manual tasks and providing support to internal users. Focusing on security proposed and implemented a private key based authentication method for web services. Was tasked with profiling applications written by others. Following new technology trends and implementing them in appropriate projects. Using Eclipse and IntelliJ IDEA as development environments, Ant and Maven 2 for project building, dependency management and deployment, JRun4 and JBoss as application servers, Oracle as backend DB. Had a short encounter with IBM DataPower hardware. Worked with eToken USB devices. Last project centered around writing an application which integrated with the qualified Certificate Authority that was being set up. I was responsible for the full development life cycle from requirements gathering to application architecture, implementation and UI design. The application was designed with a clean MVC approach using the time proven Struts framework, Spring for integration and Oracle as a backend DB. It was set up to use a two-way SSL authentication and users had to use a USB token with their personal certificate to log on.

Jul 2003 - Jul 2005 SE Centre of Registers

Java Developer

Learned JAVA and web technologies, maintained existing projects. Quickly moved on to implementing internal Web-Services using the Apache Axis framework and fixing older applications. Proposed a full rewrite for one of them due to lack of stability and lagginess. Completed the project all by myself and the result was a bug-free application with dramatic performance gains. Discovered bugs in the Jrun4 application server libraries and proposed working solutions to remedy them.

Languages

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking	Understanding
Lithuanian	Mother tongue	Mother tongue	Mother tongue	Mother tongue
English	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent
Russian	Good	Basic	Good	Fluent
German	Good	Basic	Basic	Good
Japanese	Basic	Basic	Basic	Basic

Technical Skills

Programming languages & Web technologies

Java: 7 years
JSP: 6 years
HTML: 6 years
J2EE: 4 years
JavaScript: 4 years
XML: 4 years
CSS: 4 years
Python: 4 years
C/C++: 2 years
jQuery: 1 year
Objective-C: less than a year
HTML5: less than a year
PHP: less than a year

Servers

Tomcat: 5 years

JRun4: 3 years

JBoss: 2 years

Apache HTTP: 5 years

Frameworks and tools

Struts: 4 years Maven2: 3 years Ant: 3 years SVN: 3 years Spring: 2 years Hibernate: 2 years iBatis: 1 year Git: 1 year Vim: 1 year

Other technologies

Android SDK: less than a year

Operating systems

Windows: 14 years Linux: 7 years FreeBSD: 2 years

Mac OS X: less than a year

Databases

Oracle: 4 years MySQL: 4 years PostgreSQL: 1 year

Methodologies

Scrum: 2 years TDD: 2 years

Certificates

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform, Standard Edition 5.0 (CX-310-055)

Courses

Japanese language course at the VU Centre of Oriental Studies